SHELLY GREEN

shellywiley@gmail.com | H: 404-844-9699 | Hampton, GA - Georgia 30228

Summary

Expert IT professional with quality assurance tester skills offering over 10 years of experience in detailed technical specifications. Provides collaborative style and has well-developed communication skills.

Skills

- Experience in manual & automated testing.
- Knowledgeable in Open-Source Automation tools.
- Strong foundation in Jira and Jenkins tools.
- Experience with running SQL queries.

- UNIX/LINUX
- Amazon Web Services
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Technical help desk experience

Experience

12/2010 - 12/2019 Verizon Wireless Alpharetta, GA

Systems Engineer

- Provided 24X7 front line support for UNIX and AWS cloud based applications.
- Created and tested scripts used to resolve production outages and issues.
- Monitored the performance of backend systems by executing backend shell scripts and sql database queries.
- Worked closely with business users to support production issues reported via web ticketing system.
- Created sql queries for users to extract data for on demand reports .
- Facilitated crisis management call to address and resolve production issues in a timely manner.
- Participated in QA testing for code releases.
- Performed production code installs via unix scripts as well as AWS cloud installs.

09/1996 - 12/2010 Verizon Wireless Alpharetta, GA -Georgia

Quality Assurance Analyst

- Designed and updated test cases to complete consistent manual tests.
- Performed system, unit, acceptance, regression, and performance testing on applications using both automated and manual testing methods.
- Identified and documented issues and reported them via issue tracking software.
- Worked closely with developers and business users to develop technical requirements to document and create user stories for testing purposes.
- Facilitated weekly status meeting with report testing status and resolve any issues.
- Created, edited, and updated project manuals and technical documentation used by the entire QA team.
- Explored new technologies and tools that quality assurance team could use for testing purposes.

04/1995 - 09/1996 GTE Mobilnet Atlanta, GA

Customer Support Specialist

- Informed customers about billing procedures, processed payments and provided payment option setup assistance.
- Evaluated customer account information to assess current issues and determine potential solutions.
- Upheld high standards of customer services by responding to inquiries, needs and problems.

- Analyzed customer complaints and service trends to identify and correct systematic issues.
- Applied consultative approach to collect information on customer service, account and technical concerns.
- Responded quickly to customer inquiries, needs and problems.

Education and Training

Indianapolis, IN Education

Indiana University - Purdue University Indianapolis

Schaumburg, IL **Some College (No Degree)** in Information Technology

American InterContinental University